Andrew Lee

3100 Creek Bend Dr., Friendswood TX, 77546

(832) 551 4975 Sayledgeacademy@icloud.com

Bright, motivated, responsible college student with strong experience developing and deploying software in a collaborative environment, designing with CAD tools, and integrating on FIRST robotic platforms. Taught introduction to Java classes and tutored algebra. Excellent academic, civics, and community service record. Team member and mentor for several FIRST Robotics teams. Currently studying Computer Science at University of Houston (set to graduate Fall '25). Will provide solutions and finish projects in a professional and urgent manner.



Work Experience

- CHEVRON, May 2023 August 2023
 - Designed and prototyped an automated feedback collection and processing app using the Microsoft Power Apps. I worked with team members across the US, Australia, and the Philippines to design a smart feedback request app that integrated with existing databases and communication programs. My app provided automated, targeted, and low-friction client feedback during Agile product development cycles.
- CHEVRON, May 2022 August 2022
 - Established a process mining and governance model for the PSCM Process Mining initiative. Learned Power BI, Power Apps, Celonis, Process Advisor, and produced the op model workflow to action on bottlenecks identified via the process mining tools. My op-model continues to be used as a technical resource for teams implementing and using Celonis into their own platforms.
- COPY DR, August 2021 Present
 - Customer service, print job intake, processing, and finishing, weekend manager
- APACHE INDUSTRIAL, March 2020 August 2020
 - Helped design, manufacture, and program a human-assisted motorized sanitization cart.



Technical Skills and Tools

Fluent with Java and Python; Familiar with C++, Dart, SQL; Autodesk Fusion 360, Onshape; Android Studio, VS Code, MS Office, MS Power Apps, Power BI, MS Process Advisor



Accomplishments

2017-2020

FIRST TECH CHALLENGE

Software Lead, Electrical Lead, Robot Integration Lead

- Advanced to Worlds Championship Houston for 4 consecutive years (2017-2020)
- As Software Lead.
 - Designed and implemented a series of algorithms based off of pursuit-vector navigation concepts which enabled the robot to utilize the omni-directional capabilities of its chassis more efficiently than even human drivers.
 - Built a new flexible system of programming that cut code deployment time by 80% and enabled the team to create customized autonomous strategies for each match at the 2019 FIRST World Championship.
- As Electrical Lead, fabricated custom cables and harnesses for the robot's electronics.
- As Robot Integration Lead, designed and assembled major robot subassemblies using CAD
- Won FIRST's Dean's List Finalist award (2019)
- Think Award Finalist at Worlds (2019)
- Think Award Finalist at Worlds, Inspire Award Finalist at Worlds (2018)
- 3rd Place Project award (2017)



Education

- UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON (GRADUATE FALL '25)
- **♦ TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY, THE ENGINEERING ACADEMY AT RELLIS**

Volunteer Experience

ROBOTICS

- Staff at numerous different FIRST competitions every year (2017-Present)
- Developed and presented a free multi-day Intro to FTC/Beginning Java Programming workshop at San Jacinto College twice (2018-2019)
- Mentor to one FLL and three FTC teams
- Helped present a free Intro to FLL workshop (2017)
- Taught beginning Java programming

COMMUNITY

- Tutored a semester of algebra (2019)
- Helped clean out two houses flooded by Hurricane Harvey (2017)

CHURCH

- Help with A/V and livestream (2019-2022)